https://www.tu-dortmund.de/en/privacy/?L=0

Students
Here students will find a wide range of in­for­mation for the time before, during and after their studies.
International Students
General Student Committee (AStA)
Prospective Students
Finding the right course of study is not so easy. TU Dort­mund University helps with numerous orientation and advisory services.
International Students
General Student Committee (AStA)
Partners
TU Dort­mund University works closely with partners in the promotion of in­ter­na­tio­nal exchange and the internationalization of the uni­ver­si­ty.
Press and Public Relations
The Office of University Com­mu­ni­ca­tions answers press inquiries, sends media in­for­mation and grants filming permits.
Guests
TU Dort­mund University looks forward to welcoming interested visitors and in­ter­na­tio­nal researchers to its campus.
University
Communicative, in­no­va­ti­ve, unique – that’s TU Dort­mund University.
Research
TU Dort­mund University conducts internationally outstanding research, particularly in four profile areas.
Studies
TU Dort­mund University offers study programs both in science and engineering as well as social sciences and culture studies.
International Students
General Student Committee (AStA)
Transfer
TU Dort­mund University promotes start-ups and encourages knowledge transfer from science to practice.
Campus
The campus is not only a place for learning, but also offers the opportunity to participate in various leisure activities.
Career
TU Dort­mund University offers a wide range of career opportunities in science, administration and technology.
International
TU Dort­mund University is connected to the world through student exchanges and in­ter­na­tio­nal research contacts in a variety of ways.
Meta
Suggestions?PrivacyImprintAccessibility StatementContactSitemap
You are here:
Home
Privacy
General Preliminary Remarks
The organizational unit mentioned above and the IT and Media Center (ITMC) of  TU Dort­mund University take the protection of personal data very seriously. We process personal data which are collected when visiting our websites in compliance with the applicable data protection regulations. In particular, the North-Rhine Westphalia Data Protection Act (DSG NRW), the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the German Teleservices Act (TMG) apply.
Contact Details of the Data Protection Officer
The Data Protection Officer of  the responsible person of TU Dort­mund University can be reached at:
TU Dort­mund University Data Protection Officer
August-Schmidt-Str. 4 44227 Dort­mund Germany Phone: +49 (0)231-755 2593 Send email
I. Scope of Processing of Personal Data
We only process personal data of our users if this is necessary to provide a functional website and if this is required to make our contents and services available. The processing of personal data of our users takes place as a rule only after consent of the user. An exception applies in those cases where prior consent cannot be obtained for factual reasons and the processing of the data is permitted under statutory regulations.
II. Data Erasure and Duration of Storage
The personal data of the data subject will be erased or made unavailable as soon as the purpose of storage ceases to apply. Furthermore, data may be stored if this has been provided for by the European or national legislator in EU regulations, laws or other ordinances to which the responsible person is subject. The data will also be made unavailable or erased if a storage period prescribed by the named norms expires, unless the continued storage of the data is necessary for the conclusion or fulfillment of a contract.
III. Provision of the Website and Creation of Log Files
1. Description and scope of data processing
Each time our website is accessed, our system automatically collects data and in­for­mation from the computer system of the accessing computer.
The following data are collected here: Information about the browser type and version used Operating system of the user IP address of the user Date and time of access The data are also stored in the log files of our system. A storage of this data together with other personal data of the user does not take place.
2. Purpose and legal basis for data processing
The temporary storage of the IP address by the system is necessary to allow delivery of the website to the computer of the user. For this purpose, the user's IP address must be stored for the duration of the session. (Necessity for the fulfillment of the task of the uni­ver­si­ty Art. 6 (1) (e) GDPR)
Storage in log files is done to ensure the functionality of the website. In addition, the data are used to optimize the website and to ensure the security of our in­for­mation technology systems. An evaluation of the data for marketing purposes does not take place in this context. (Necessity for the fulfillment of the task of the uni­ver­si­ty Art. 6 (1) (e) GDPR).
3. Duration of storage
Processing will take place during use until the end of each session.
If the data are stored in log files, this is the case for a maximum of 24 hours. After that, the IP addresses of the users are anonymized, so that an assignment to the accessing client is no longer possible.
IV. Rights of the Person Concerned
If your personal data are processed, you are affected within the meaning of the GDPR, and you have the following rights vis-à-vis the responsible person:
If you want to exercise your rights, please contact the Data Protection Officer of TU Dort­mund University.
1. Right of access by the data subject (Art. 15 GDPR)
You have the right to in­for­mation about personal data concerning you that is collected, processed or, if relevant, transferred to third parties.
2. Right to object (Art. 21 GDPR)
You have the right to object to the processing of your personal data if the processing is based on Art. 6 (1) e or f  GDPR.
3. Right to erasure (Art. 17 GDPR)
In particular, after the legally prescribed retention periods have expired, you have the right to have your data erased.
4. Right to restriction of processing (Art. 18 GDPR)
In special cases, you have the right to restrict processing. This is the case if the data processing is unlawful, if you dispute the accuracy of the data collected or if you have filed an objection to the processing. You can also request a restriction of the processing if the data are subject to an erasure obligation because the purpose of the processing has been achieved, but you need these data to assert legal claims. You must request a processing restriction.
5. Right to rectification (Art. 16 GDPR)
You have the right to have incorrect personal data rectified.
6. Right to revoke the data protection consent declaration (Art. 7 GDPR)
You have the right to revoke your data protection declaration of consent at any time. The revocation of consent does not affect the legality of the processing carried out on the basis of the consent until revocation.
7. Right to complain to a supervisory authority
If you have any questions or complaints regarding data protection, you can always contact a data protection supervisory authority. In our case, the State Commissioner for Data Protection and Freedom of Information in North Rhine-Westphalia is responsible.
Please note that this privacy policy does not apply to all parts of the TU Dort­mund University website.
V. Use of YouTube Videos
On our website, we offer users the opportunity to view selected videos from YouTube directly on the site. In order to protect user data, a link to YouTube is established by clicking on a link and the video is started. Only then will data be sent to the provider. If you do not click on the link, there will be no exchange between the user and YouTube. Information about the collection and use of your data on YouTube can be found here.
VI. Web analytics by Matomo (formerly PIWIK)
1. Scope of processing of personal data
We use the open-source software tool Matomo (formerly PIWIK) on our website to analyze the surfing behavior of our users. The software works with session cookies, which assign online activities to a single browser session and are usually deleted after the browser is closed. The following data is saved when individual pages of our website are accessed: Two bytes of the IP address of the accessing user system The website accessed The website from which the user accesses the requested page (referrer) The sub-pages accessed from the website visited The time spent on the webpage How often the website is accessed The software only runs on our website servers. The user’s personal data is only saved to the website server. The data is not shared with third parties.
You can disable Matomo by unchecking the following box to turn on the opt-out plugin:
Name and Address of the Responsible Person
The responsible person within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation and other national data protection laws of the member states as well as other data protection regulations is:
TU Dort­mund University The President
TU Dort­mund University August-Schmidt-Str. 4 44227 Dort­mund Germany Phone:  +49 (0)231/755-1
To top of page
Search & People Search
Deutsch
Cafeteria menus
Location & approach
Service­Portal
UniMail
Search & People Search
By car
The campus of TU Dort­mund University is located close to interstate junction Dort­mund West, where the Sauerlandlinie A 45 (Frankfurt-Dort­mund) crosses the Ruhrschnellweg B 1 / A 40. The best interstate exit to take from A 45 is "Dort­mund-Eichlinghofen" (closer to Campus Süd), and from B 1 / A 40 "Dort­mund-Dorstfeld" (closer to Campus Nord). Signs for the uni­ver­si­ty are located at both exits. Also, there is a new exit before you pass over the B 1-bridge leading into Dort­mund.
To get from Campus Nord to Campus Süd by car, there is the connection via Vogelpothsweg/Baroper Straße. We recommend you leave your car on one of the parking lots at Campus Nord and use the H-Bahn (suspended monorail system), which conveniently connects the two campuses.
By train
TU Dort­mund University has its own train station ("Dort­mund Uni­ver­si­tät"). From there, suburban trains (S-Bahn) leave for Dort­mund main station ("Dort­mund Hauptbahnhof") and Düsseldorf main station via the "Düsseldorf Airport Train Station" (take S-Bahn number 1, which leaves every 20 or 30 minutes). The uni­ver­si­ty is easily reached from Bochum, Essen, Mülheim an der Ruhr and Duisburg.
You can also take the bus or subway train from Dort­mund city to the uni­ver­si­ty: From Dort­mund main station, you can take any train bound for the Station "Stadtgarten", usually lines U41, U45, U 47 and U49. At "Stadtgarten" you switch trains and get on line U42 towards "Hombruch". Look out for the Station "An der Palmweide". From the bus stop just across the road, busses bound for TU Dort­mund University leave every ten minutes (445, 447 and 462). Another option is to take the subway routes U41, U45, U47 and U49 from Dort­mund main station to the stop "Dort­mund Kampstraße". From there, take U43 or U44 to the stop "Dort­mund Wittener Straße". Switch to bus line 447 and get off at "Dort­mund Uni­ver­si­tät S".
By plane
The AirportExpress is a fast and convenient means of transport from Dort­mund Airport (DTM) to Dort­mund Central Station, taking you there in little more than 20 minutes. From Dort­mund Central Station, you can continue to the uni­ver­si­ty campus by interurban railway (S-Bahn). A larger range of in­ter­na­tio­nal flight connections is offered at Düsseldorf Airport (DUS), which is about 60 kilometres away and can be directly reached by S-Bahn from the uni­ver­si­ty station.
The H-Bahn (Suspended Monorail System)
The H-Bahn is one of the hallmarks of TU Dort­mund University. There are two stations on Campus Nord. One ("Dort­mund Uni­ver­si­tät S") is directly located at the suburban train stop, which connects the uni­ver­si­ty directly with the city of Dort­mund and the rest of the Ruhr Area. Also from this station, there are connections to the "Technologiepark" and (via Campus Süd) Eichlinghofen. The other station is located at the dining hall at Campus Nord and offers a direct connection to Campus Süd every five minutes.
Map
The facilities of TU Dort­mund University are spread over two campuses, the larger Campus North and the smaller Campus South. Additionally, some areas of the uni­ver­si­ty are located in the adjacent "Technologiepark".
Site Map of TU Dort­mund University (Second Page in English)
